Abhishek Danalakota Dabhishek2895@gmail.com, +353 894503909

PROFILE

An experienced Developer Support, Technical Support, Incident and Application analyst with two years of comprehensive work experience in the technology services sector while working with fortune 500 companies on its product and service base projects, creative problem solver with exceptional troubleshooting skills, exceptional stakeholder relationships, communication skills and customer focused nature while working face to face with multiethnic clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Genpact Ireland(Client : Facebook) Developer Support Analyst

(March 2020-Present)

I work with Facebook's Platform partners, marketers, and advertisers, as the point of contact for developers, focusing on helping them build engaging and social applications using the Facebook Platform. I assist developers by providing creative solutions to challenging technical issues.

- Provide effective technical consultation to Facebook developers regarding all products and services.
- Decipher and troubleshoot bug reports and maintain communication with Product Engineering for further assessment.
- Debug code snippet and coding samples from developers and fix their issues.
- I am the point of contact for Platform developers and manage technical product issues and escalations, delivering the highest level of developer satisfaction
- Build product insights from developer experience/sentiments and work with cross-functional partners to take appropriate action.
- Writing technical emails to developers to make them understand about the issue and drive them to solution.
- · Assist developers with Facebook API integrations using Graph API Explorer
- Troubleshooting production issue related to Facebook APIs and document the processing
- Drive to meet or exceed daily performance metrics related to key performance indicators
- Engage with the operations and engineering teams to build, drive and improve our tools and processes

IBM India(Client: National Bank of Australia)

(Feb 2018 – Jan 2019)

Security Delivery Specialist

Worked as IT security delivery specialist handling Australian clients (NAB, TfNSW & TAC) and supporting them in maintaining their active directory and information security, providing infrastructural Services to Clients

- Handled the application support team responsible for Identity and access management of the clients
- Experience managing user life cycle and integrating application requirements in a shared services framework focused on provisioning, de-provisioning, entitlements and role-based access control
- Strong knowledge and experience managing the following IAM activities: ID administration, provisioning, governance/auditing, IAM reporting, IAM tool operations
- Maintained in-depth knowledge of the IBM and client products and information security best-practice
- Worked on Linux servers for providing access to new customers and stakeholders
- Experience in software development lifecycle (Agile)
- Investigate and troubleshoot issues and developing solutions for our customers while understanding their business needs

- Worked on IBM internal tools to monitor network, servers and applications
- Worked under pressure to meet the deadlines even when the team leads moved to different projects
- Resolve escalated hardware and software issues related to LAN/WAN

Nvidia India(Spectrum Consultancy)

(Jan 2017 – Feb 2018)

Intern

- Provide support to clients by responding to emails and phone calls
- Understand hierarchy of incident escalation: Night duty, supervisor, manager.
- Helped production to identify inefficiencies and suggested ways to increase productivity
- Following SOAPs set by firm and applying them efficiently where required.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Linux, Bash scripting, Python, JavaScript, PHP,
Databases	SQL, Oracle, MSSQL
Operating Systems	Windows 2000/NT/XP/Vista/7/8/10, Ubuntu, Linux, CentOS
Web Services	Azure, AWS, Oracle
Web Application & Servers	Apache Tomcat, JBOSS, REST, CSS, HTML, APIs
Incident Tools	Service Now, IT Remedy, SRT, JIRA
Tools	IBM BigFix, URT, UAT, Microsoft Office Suite, Active Directory, Wireshark, QUIP, CRM
Networking	LAN, WAN, IP, HTTP, DNS, TCP/IP, UDP, OSI model, Switching and routing
Servers	Linux Servers, Windows 2008/2012/2016, UNIX
DevOps Tools	Terraform, Git

ACHIEVEMENTS

- I am the first point of contact for whole Genpact Dublin which is achieved with in 3 months of time.
- Continuously exceeding the KPIs set example achieving more than 68% on a monthly basis
- Lean Idea tested and implemented to improve process
- Working on different adhoc tasks set by service delivery manager
- Rewritten the scripts in IBM Bigfix tool in results managed to handle as high as 600 tickets in a day.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certified (AZ-900)
- Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Second Edition)
- Agile Scrum Trained (Genpact)
- Online Basic Lean Certified (Genpact)
- Certified Network Security Specialist (CNSS)
- Certified ITIL V3 foundations (Genpact)
- · Terraform Associate certified

EXTRA CIRCULAM ACTIVITIES

- I was a part of KBC DUBLIN MARATHON 2019 given my services as helpdesk volunteer and very happy to meet new people.
- Active member of engagement activity Genpact conducting Fun @ Friday sessions leading to engage every team member from different teams to participate and make them refresh.

EDUCATION

Master's in Data Analytics, Dublin Business School

2019-2020

Completed Master's in Data Analytics in Dublin (2.1)

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science, JNT University

2013-2017

Completed Bachelor's in Computer Science with 1.1

LINKEDIN - https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-danalakota-b28582a6/